Guide to the Czechoslovakian Press Clippings Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Czechoslovakian press clippings collection
1954-1968
MS 1420
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
25
(60 boxes)
The collection consists of mimeographed copies of press reports from Czechoslovakian sources. The material was collected by David Korbel, an attorney who served as Secretary General of the Czechoslovak State Council (in exile) after the German occupation.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Slavic and East European Collection, Sterling Memorial Library, 1985.
Arrangement
Arranged in chronological order.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of mimeographed copies of press clippings and reports from Czechoslovakian sources. These materials document cultural, social, and political topics relating to Czechoslovakia from 1954 through 1968. There are no English translations for any of the items.
Custodial History
The collection was compiled by David Korbel, an attorney who served as Secretary General of the Czechoslovak State Council (in exile) after the German occupation. The materials were transferred to the Manuscripts and Archives Department from the Slavic and East European Collection in 1985.
Czechoslovakia -- History -- 1945-1992; Occupations -- Czechoslovakia; Czechoslovakia -- Politics and government -- 1945-1992; Korbel, David E., 1899-1969
- Inventory
  - 1954 January-March (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
  - 1954 March - May (Box 2, Folder 11-19)
  - 1954 May - June (Box 3, Folder 20-27)
  - 1954 July - August (Box 4, Folder 28-36)
  - 1954 August - October (Box 5, Folder 37-46)
  - 1954 October - December (Box 6, Folder 47-55)
  - 1954 December - 1955 January (Box 7, Folder 56-64)
  - 1955 February - March (Box 8, Folder 65-72)
  - 1955 March - May (Box 9, Folder 73-81)
  - 1955 June - August (Box 10, Folder 82-90)
  - 1955 August - September (Box 11, Folder 91-101)
  - 1955 November - December (Box 12, Folder 102-111)
  - 1956 January - February (Box 13, Folder 112-121)
  - 1956 March - April (Box 14, Folder 122-130)
  - 1956 April - June (Box 15, Folder 131-139)
  - 1956 June - July (Box 16, Folder 140-147)
  - 1956 August - September (Box 17, Folder 148-156)
  - 1956 October - November (Box 18, Folder 157-164)
  - 1956 December - 1957 February (Box 19, Folder 165-174)
  - 1957 February - April (Box 20, Folder 175-184)
  - 1957 April - June (Box 21, Folder 185-194)
  - 1957 July - October (Box 22, Folder 195-205)
  - 1957 October - 1958 January (Box 23, Folder 206-215)
  - 1958 February - April (Box 24, Folder 216-224)
  - 1958 May - July (Box 25, Folder 225-233)
  - 1958 August - November (Box 26, Folder 234-244)
  - 1958 November - 1959 March (Box 27, Folder 245-255)
  - 1959 March - June (Box 28, Folder 256-268)
  - 1959 July - September (Box 29, Folder 269-279)
  - 1959 September - December (Box 30, Folder 280-292)
  - 1960 January - March (Box 31, Folder 293-303)
  - 1960 April - June (Box 32, Folder 304-315)
  - 1960 July - October (Box 33, Folder 316-329)
  - 1960 October - 1961 January (Box 34, Folder 330-342)
  - 1961 February - April (Box 35, Folder 343-355)
  - 1961 May - July (Box 36, Folder 357-367)
  - 1961 August - November (Box 37, Folder 370-385)
  - 1961 December - 1962 March (Box 38, Folder 386-398)
  - 1962 April - July (Box 39, Folder 399-412)
  - 1962 August - November (Box 40, Folder 413-423)
  - 1962 November - 1963 February (Box 41, Folder 424-437)
  - 1963 March - May (Box 42, Folder 438-449)
  - 1963 June - August (Box 43, Folder 450-459)
  - 1963 September - November (Box 44, Folder 460-474)
  - 1963 December - 1964 March (Box 45, Folder 475-493)
  - 1964 April - July (Box 46, Folder 494-510)
  - 1964 July - October (Box 47, Folder 511-527)
  - 1964 November - 1965 February (Box 48, Folder 528-542)
  - 1965 March - June (Box 49, Folder 543-559)
  - 1965 July - November (Box 50, Folder 560-579)
  - 1965 November - 1966 March (Box 51, Folder 580-597)
  - 1966 March - July (Box 52, Folder 598-617)
  - 1966 August - October (Box 53, Folder 618-644)
  - 1966 November - 1967 March (Box 54, Folder 645-666)
  - 1967 April - July (Box 55, Folder 667-683)
  - 1967 August - November (Box 56, Folder 684-698)
  - 1967 December - 1968 March (Box 57, Folder 699-707)
  - 1968 April - July (Box 58, Folder 708-718)
  - 1968 July - November (Box 59, Folder 719-732)
  - 1968 December (Box 60, Folder 733-738)